# 家家都做的 特别特别家常的
All families know how to cook this homely dish.
# 让你意想不到的效果
A result you would never expect.
# 糊塌子
Hu tazi (zucchini pancake)
# 五星级糊塌子
5 star hu tazi
# 您嚼嚼 特别有意思
Have a taste, it’s an interesting flavour
# 你这擦子不错
This grater’s not bad
# 师父您看这个 我选的是最大（孔）的
Master, have a look, I’m using the side with the biggest holes
# 因为吃糊塌子的时候口感好 有嚼劲
This gives it an incredible, chewy texture
# 好 擦好了
Alright, we’ve finished grating
# 现在往里撒点盐 差不多二十克一勺
Now add about 20g of salt (1 spoon)
# 然后把糊塌子杀一下
to extract the water
# 糊塌子咱有蘸汁
We’ll make a sauce for it
# 这个（盐）还不能放太多
Don’t add too much salt
# 大爷 女大厨
Da Ye, here we have a top female chef
# 新国贸饭店的行政总厨
The head chef at Hotel Jen Beijing
# 北京市十大名厨技能大赛时候
When she was at the competition of Beijing’s top ten chefs
# 把那九个男的全给挫败了
She beat all nine male chefs
# 女中豪杰 姣姣者
A true hero among women, and beautiful too
# 这个我们磕五粒鸡蛋
Here we crack 5 eggs
# 这是洗过的鸡蛋
These are washed eggs
# 我们把鸡蛋搅一搅
Let's beat the eggs
# 为什么 就让蛋液里
Why? To make sure
# 有充分的空气在里边
there is enough air in the eggs
# 然后它的饼 糊塌子喧乎 松软
This makes it soft and fluffy
# 一般家里就直接把鸡蛋和到面里了
Most people would just crack the eggs directly into the dough
# 所以每一个环节都很重要
So every step is important
# 打鸡蛋尽量朝一个方向打
Beat the eggs in one direction as much as you can
# 这就不像咱们家里
This isn’t how we usually
# 一般的打鸡蛋了是吧
beat the eggs at home right?
# 抽这鸡蛋能感觉到鸡蛋
You can feel the egg as you beat it
# 它没那么大劲了
It’s not as heavy anymore
# 慢慢的跟水似的 泡沫也多了
It slowly becomes water-like liquid, with lots of bubbles forming
# 好 泡沫多了 我们就
Ok, when lots of bubbles have formed
# 下一步西葫芦的汁也出来了
For the next step, the water has now came out from the zucchini
# 然后我们小心一些
then we have to be a bit more careful now
# 把这鸡蛋液 防止它有蛋皮在里边
Pour the egg mixture out
# 我们小心的给它倒出来
to prevent settled pieces going through
# 你看每一个环节这个都是细心
You see, every step is very carefully handled
# 现在我们把蛋液和西葫芦
Now we mix the egg
# 充分的拌匀了
and zucchini mixture until it’s even
# 这时候就放面粉了
then it’s time to add flour
# 刚才西葫芦有一斤多
We used about 1 jin (500g) of zucchini
# 我们的面粉是差不多六百五十克
so we will add around 650g of flour
# 这个比例大概齐就是1:1
The proportion is roughly 1:1
# 我们先把面粉和西葫芦鸡蛋拌匀
First we mix the mixture evenly
# 这个面粉是低筋面就可以
This flour we’re using is low gluten (cake flour)
# 要是劲大了的话
If you use a lot of force while mixing
# 它出来的饼 糊塌子它会硬
the texture will end up too hard
# 一碗面真正的是一碗水
One bowl of flour, one bowl of water
# 一碗面一碗水 五个鸡蛋
One bowl of flour, one bowl of water and five eggs
# 一碗面一碗水
One bowl of flour, one bowl of water
# 大家就把握这个稀稠程度
You need to master the consistency
# 感觉提溜起来的状态
Feel the texture as you hold it like this
# 就很快滑落下去了从手里边 就行了
When it easily falls from your hand
# 看这样 这就差不多了
Look, just like this. When it’s like this, it’s ready
# 齐活 还差最后一步
And that’s everything! There’s still one last step
# 香油一勺 两勺
Sesame oil! One spoon, two spoons
# 看着啊 混合均匀
Have a look, mix evenly
# 搁油是什么目的呢
What’s the purpose of the oil?
# 使糊塌子更加松软 香
It makes the Hu tazi even softer, and fragrant too
# 这个就真的齐活了
Now it is all done!
# 先搁着 然后还有一个秘密
Leave it aside first, there’s still another secret tip
# 我心中藏着一个小秘密
My heart hides a small secret (song lyrics)
# 不能告诉你
which I can’t tell you
# 下一节目 这是什么肉啊
Time for the next step. What kind of meat is this?
# 酱牛肉 酱牦牛肉
Soy braised beef, yak meat
# 现在快节奏的生活
Nowadays the pace of life is so fast
# 这一盘荤素全有了
This dish has both meat and vegetables
# 就算一简单的食品
Even if it is a simple dish
# 穿心莲 去火啊
Chuan Xin Lian, this make you feel cool and comfortable
# 也是有准备而来啊
You’ve come prepared!
# 有准备 她说了不能让师父失望
She came prepared, saying she couldn’t let Master be disappointed
# 不能让大爷绝望
Can’t let Da Ye down
# 怎么那么会编排我啊
How could you guys set me up like this
# 好了 撒点盐省的滑 砸点烂蒜
Alright. Sprinkle some salt and crush some garlic
# 这个就是糊塌子的汁 蒜泥汁
This is the sauce for Hu tazi, garlic sauce
# 好我们蒜泥打出来了
We’ve crushed the garlic into garlic paste
# 这个是香草醋 意大利香草醋
This is balsamic vinegar from Italy
# 这个香醋米醋都可以
Balsamic vinegar or rice vinegar, either works.
# 生抽我们少来一点 醋多
Add a small amount of soy sauce with a higher amount of vinegar
# 实际上外国醋
Actually, these foreign vinegars
# 香草醋也好 苹果醋也好
Balsamic vinegar, apple cider vinegar
# 它的醋的酸味特别稳定
The acidity is very stable
# 香油 香油的比例就是个人的爱好
Some sesame oil, add according to your own preferences
# 你像过去姥姥活着那个年代
You cook similar to my grandmom’s generation
# 就搁两滴香油 家里没香油
Only two drops of sesame oil, no sesame oil in the house
# 但是那两滴香油真香
But with just those two drops, it’s still truly fragrant
# 这汁我们就和好了
We have now finished making this sauce
# 点火 来点底油
Light the fire and pour in some oil
# 做饼不建议用特别旺的火
We don’t suggest using high heat
# 小一些的火 它喧腾 好
Use a smaller flame, just enough to make it sizzle
# 听这声 合适
Listen to this sound
# 能听着这滋啦滋啦的声
When you hear this sound
# 也可以备一个小板儿
You can prepare a pancake spreader
# 这家里的小板我也有这个
I’ve also got one of those here
# 煎饼的小刮板用在这了
We use the pancake scraper here
# 您看这上面的糊没有了 它都变黄了
Look, there’s no more dough on the top, it has turned yellow
# 证明这个就起来了
This means that it has started to rise
# 这一面都变成黄色以后
After this side has turned yellow
# 翻
Flip
# 一点都没有起嘎巴
Hasn’t been burned one bit
# 受热均匀
Let it heat evenly
# 为什么叫虎皮糊塌子
Why is it called "tiger skin hu tazi"?
# 您看它这个焦状特别美
Look here, it looks especially beautiful when it’s cooked
# 精彩
Amazing
# 黄的绿的再加上金色的
Yellow, green and gold
# 好出锅 漂亮
Alright, take it out of the pan. Beautiful
# 这个必须戴着手套做
You must wear gloves for this part
# 同样一煎饼 它就产生一种
It’s the same as jian bing (Chinese savoury pancake). It produces a kind of
# 让你意想不到的效果 齐
effect which you would never expect. Finished
# 装盘儿
Time for plating
# 你看高宁这一装饰
See how Gao Ning (name) has plated this
# 就不像咱们一摊
Unlike how we would
# 摊一大张往那一搁 跟烙饼似的
Spread it out wide and roll it one way Just like a pancake
# 五星级糊塌子
5 star hu tazi
# 白糖
White sugar
# 尽量把这白糖不撒在糊塌子上
Try not to sprinkle this on the hu tazi
# 让它在牦牛肉和穿心莲上边
Sprinkle it on the meat and chuan tin lian
# 我们现在浇汁
Now we pour the sauce on top
# 这个又是一种吃法
This is also a way of eating
# 您嚼嚼 特别有意思
Have a taste, it’s an interesting flavour
# 文吃
This is civilised way of eating
# 味道醇厚 加上蒜香味浓 特别精彩
A simple and rich flavour, and with the fragrant garlic paste on top it is truly amazing.
# 绝搭 再来个糊塌子
A perfect pairing, let’s have another
# 这个汁调得好
This sauce has been seasoned very well
# 香草醋有一种特殊的香味
Balsamic vinegar has a special aroma.
# 这个跟咱们那米醋有不同的口感
The flavour is different to our rice vinegar
# 一个平平常常的糊塌子吃食
An ordinary Hu tazi but when you eat it
# 每个层次的味道还是不一样
every layer has a different flavour
# 给高宁一个大赞
Give Gao Ning a like!